Samuel Grasse-Haroldsen

Eugene, Oregon (willing to relocate) | 208-243-7886 | sgrasseharoldsen@gmail.com github.com/SamG-H | dev.to/szam | samuelgh.com | linkedin.com/in/samuel-grasse-haroldsen

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Ruby, JavaScript, and C++ based programming with a background in quality assurance. Possess strong skills in debugging and collaborating with others. Driven change in quality assurance inspections to guarantee customer satisfaction and improved training processes for new employees. Helped teammates debug issues and better understand the development process. Flexible with learning new skills and working with people internationally.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages - Ruby, SQL, JavaScript, C++, HTML, CSS

Frameworks - Rails, Sinatra, React, Redux

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

flipr - github.com/SamG-H/flipr | github.com/SamG-H/flipr backend

An SPA allowing users to create and flip through stacks of flashcards - (Vanilla JS front-end with a Rails API)

- Replaced ActiveModel::Serializer with fast isonapi resulting in huge performance boost
- Implemented single fetch calls for individual stacks so app can easily scale

Flipr Quiz - github.com/SamG-H/flipr quiz

A React app that accesses the flipr backend and generates guizzes based on the stacks of flashcards

- Used Redux coupled with Thunk to manage state and make fetch calls
- Utilized core React features such as lifecycle methods, controlled forms, components, and props

Forge & Fix - github.com/SamG-H/forge-and-fix

A Rails web app for people to share ideas and work on projects together.

- Utilized Bulma framework to make a simple clean UI
- Took advantage of a custom SQL query to boost performance when ordering projects by issue count
- Employed OmniAuth to add third-party GitHub authentication

fruit-info - github.com/SamG-H/fruit-cli-gem | rubygems.org/gems/fruit-info

A Ruby command line app that retrieves information from the fruityvice API and allows the user to interact with the data

- Used HTTParty Ruby gem to easily retrieve data from API
- Took advantage of mass assignment within Ruby cutting down on code length
- Published on rubygems.org where gem has over 250 downloads

EXPERIENCE

Melaleuca Rexburg, Idaho Assistant QA Tech 12/2018 - 05/2020

- Inspected incoming job components/ingredients, finished goods, and lab tested dietary supplements/cleaning products.
- Drove change in training process resulting in improved manufacturing practices.
- Set new records in number of inspections completed driving higher standards/benchmarks

Faith-Based Organization

Advocate

Budapest, Hungary 09/2014 - 12/2016

• Taught English, helped people change addictive behaviours, and learned Hungarian.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Online Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program 06/2020 - 11/2020

Brigham Young University-Idaho

Rexburg, Idaho

Completed 52 credits towards Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering

01/2017 - 12/2018